<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="to_html.xslt"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="to_html.xslt"?><page>
  <title>ActionGrid - Context Menu with Data</title>
  <titleorder />
  <description />
  <content>&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this guide is to show how we can see from the context menu to an &lt;strong&gt;ActionGrid&lt;/strong&gt; the data we want, in another page.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;To begin with we will SELECT within the generator, in this case we are using the Northwind Customers table  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="images/images_adb/selectcustomers.gif"&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Once the query is made we click on "Generate Grid", to generate a grid. After the XML configuration has been created, we will go to the "XML Grid Editor" tab to edit the XML configuration.  &lt;p&gt;Under "5.- Grid Columns" we will edit the columns that make up this grid. As in the SELECT statement all the columns have been included "*" the generator will use them all by default.  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="images/images_adb/EditGridColumnsCollection.gif"&gt;  &lt;p&gt;We select some columns that we will remove.  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="images/images_adb/selectcolumns.gif"&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Next we will edit the context menu in this section before creating the various items from which this context menu will be made up, we specify the fields we want to use to call URLs, in this case we want to transfer the CUSTOMERID’s column value to another page.  &lt;p&gt;For this reason, we will enter the column name in fields.  &lt;p&gt;In Formats, we must establish and match the name of one of the fields that we have previously established in Fields, and assign a code that we will use later to replace. This code will be later replaced by the CUSTOMERID value.  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="images/images_adb/EditContextMenuRedir1.gif"&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Once these fields have been assigned, we can create the ContextMenuItem; we'll add a new context menu and we'll assign an image from layouts, we will give it a name (in this case "View Orders") and finally we will add the page to which we want to be redirected in the URL.  &lt;p&gt;In the URL we will specify the CustomersOrders.aspx page, the&amp;nbsp; parameter’s name that we are going to transfer in this case “CustomerID" and&amp;nbsp; its value, in this case %Cust%&amp;nbsp; that at the time when it will be called will be replaced by the column CUSTOMERID value that we are in.  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="images/images_adb/EditContextMenuRedir2.gif"&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="images/images_adb/EditContextMenuRedir3.gif"&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Once the process is completed, we will accept the changes and we will generate the XML.  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="images/images_adb/EditContextMenuRedirXML.gif"&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Finally we will copy the contents into an &lt;strong&gt;ActionGrid&lt;/strong&gt;, and the result will be as follows  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="images/images_adb/EditContextMenuRedirEnd.gif"&gt;  &lt;p&gt;By clicking on "View Orders" we will be redirected to the&amp;nbsp; "CustomersOrders.aspx" page in this case&amp;nbsp; the url will be CustomersOrders.aspx?CustomerID=ANATR&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  <keywords />
  <parent>eb91727f-c6e5-4d84-b9dd-c5773e2261eb</parent>
  <isfrontpage>False</isfrontpage>
  <showinlist>True</showinlist>
  <ispublished>True</ispublished>
  <datecreated>2008-05-08 11:30:11</datecreated>
  <datemodified>2008-05-08 11:30:11</datemodified>
</page>