<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="to_html.xslt"?><page>
  <title>ActionDataBase - Connecting</title>
  <titleorder />
  <description />
  <content>&lt;p&gt;In this part of the Quick Start Guide we will see how to connect an &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;ActionDataBaseGrid&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; to an &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;ActionDataBaseEditor&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;.  &lt;p&gt;- The first thing we will do is to edit the&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt; ActionDataBaseGrid&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;, in order to add a context menu, the context menu will contain an option that will allow us to select a data row. At the time that the&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt; ActionDataBaseGrid&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; is connected to another webpart, the ActionDataBaseGrid will provide all the values from the selected row.  &lt;p&gt;-To do this we can use the configuration we have in the generator, if we have closed it we can copy the settings in the properties and paste it into the advanced editor.  &lt;p&gt;- In this last case, open the WebPart properties select XML configuration and copy it.  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="images/images_adb/WebParts_XMLConfigurationSelectAll.gif"&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="images/images_adb/WebParts_XMLConfigurationCopy.gif"&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;-Open again the generator, and go to the 'XML Grid Editor " tab  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="images/images_adb/Generator_GridXMLTabGetFromClipboard.gif"&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;- Click on "Get from Clipboard" to recover the XML configuration.  &lt;p&gt;- You can now use the Advanced Editor to edit the configuration file.  &lt;p&gt;- The advanced editor contains all XML configuration file sections, we will go to "Grid Columns"  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="images/images_adb/Generator_XMLGridEditor_Columns.gif"&gt;  &lt;p&gt;- To edit the columns we must click on the icon to the right  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="images/images_adb/Generator_EditCollectionButton.gif"&gt;  &lt;p&gt;-A new window will open and in this window we can edit the grid columns configuration.  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="images/images_adb/Generator_XMLGridEditor_ColumnsCollection.gif"&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;- We will only leave three columns (CompanyName, ContactName and ContactTitle).  &lt;p&gt;- Note: To optimise the &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;ActionDataBaseGrid&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; running, we should leave in the query SELECT, only those columns that we are going to use. It is not strictly necessary, but it benefits the performance. In this case, although we will only show the CompanyName, ContactName and ContactTitle columns, we will also use the contacts columns; So if we have opted for the consultation optimization, these four columns should be the ones that should appear in the SELECT clause.  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="images/images_adb/Generator_XMLGridEditor_ColumnsCollection1.gif"&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;- We will add the context menu in the "CompanyName" column, to do this we will dropdown the Context menu And we will add a new ContextMenuItem to the collection.  &lt;p&gt;- The collection will be empty if we have not added anything earlier.  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="images/images_adb/Generator_XMLGridEditor_ContextMenuItemCollection.gif"&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;To add a new ContextMenuItem, we just click on the icon "Add" and complete the properties.  &lt;p&gt;- The ContextMenuItem properties are three. The image address that we want to show in the menu, the text that we want to show and the URL where we want to be re-directed.  &lt;p&gt;-In this case what we want to do is to select a full row, so we will use a reserved word "Row", which will be the one that will tell the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;ActionDataBaseGrid&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to select the row in which we find ourselves. We will explain this later.  &lt;p&gt;- In the Image property, we can specify any of the images that SharePoint has, we can find these in / _layouts / images. As an example the configuration would be displayed like this.  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="images/images_adb/Generator_XMLGridEditor_ContextMenuItemSelectRow.gif"&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;-We will accept the configuration until returning to the beginining "XML Grid Editor" tab.  &lt;p&gt;- click on the icon "Generate XML"  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="images/images_adb/Generator_GenerateButton.gif"&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;- And the new configuration will be available.  &lt;p&gt;- Copy the new configuration and paste it into the of &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;ActionDataBaseGrid&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; WebPart properties.  &lt;p&gt;- We will accept the changes and our Grid should have this look/appearance/aspect.  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="images/images_adb/ActionDataBaseGrid_FirstContextMenu.gif"&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;- If we display the context menu, we will see the option that we have created.  &lt;p&gt;- If we click on it nothing will happens. First we must connect our &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;ActionDataBaseGrid&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; to another WebPart, with the &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;ActionDataBaseEditor&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;.  &lt;p&gt;- Therefore, we must select in the webpart editing menu, and select to which webpart we want to send the data.  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="images/images_adb/ActionDataBaseGrid_Connecting.gif"&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;-After selecting the webpart where we want to send data, we have to indicate which data we want to fit through the dialogue box.  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="images/images_adb/ActionDataBaseGrid_Connecting1.gif"&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;-The connection window will ask us what grid server we want to connect to the fields that are available to the consumer.  &lt;p&gt;- By default when we generate the &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;ActionDataBaseEdito&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;, the generator identifies the identity fields from the table and they are the ones who are available as consumers.  &lt;p&gt;- In this case we will link the &lt;i&gt;CustomerID&lt;/i&gt; field with the CUSTOMER the one who is expecting to receive the publisher that will allow him to view the data.  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="images/images_adb/ActionDataBaseGrid_Connecting2.gif"&gt;  &lt;p&gt;-- Then we will click on "Next", the server, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;ActionDataBaseGrid&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, will continue to offer us all the columns that are in the SELECT clause. You will discard them as we don’t need them.  &lt;p&gt;- Upon completion of the transaction, we will see the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;ActionDataBaseEditor&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; register  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="images/images_adb/ActionDataBaseGrid_Connected.gif"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  <keywords />
  <parent>00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000000000</parent>
  <isfrontpage>False</isfrontpage>
  <showinlist>True</showinlist>
  <ispublished>True</ispublished>
  <datecreated>2008-04-28 23:11:18</datecreated>
  <datemodified>2008-04-28 23:12:30</datemodified>
</page>